# Erdni Zergetaev

+77053693218 | zergetaev@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/zernie

### Summary

Senior Full Stack web developer with 7 years of experience and a project management skillset.

Worked on large websites with millions of users, cutting-edge startups and legacy codebases.

Open to remote contracts and visa sponsorship proposals.

#### Professional Skills

Rails, React, Redux, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, Rspec, Docker, Jquery, Node.js, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Stimulus.js, Next.js, Ethereum, Web3

#### Work experience

#### Archive.com

## Senior Staff Software Developer | 01/2022 - Present

- Being an early core employee I had a hand in the hiring process, conducting 30+ rigorous technical interviews for the
  position of Senior Software Developers, which resulted in 3 accepted job offers. All of the hirees have been top-5
  performers so far.
- Became a part-time project manager for one of the our product offerings a Shoppables product gallery, which now has a
  waiting list of 10+ big customers waiting for onboarding.
- Performed a large-scale frontend refactoring, gradually adding TypeScript to the codebase which had reduced the amount
  of bugs in production by an order.

### Bonfire | San Francisco, California

### Senior Full Stack Developer (remote) | 05/2021 - 09/2021

- Implemented an airdrops feature on blockchain which helped to attract dozens of new B2B clients and **tens of thousands of dollars** in Monthly Recurring Revenue
- Refactored parts of codebase, increased test coverage with Jest to **70%**, added sound typings which allowed to fix financial bugs and save thousands of dollars monthly on support
- Built a solid archectural foundation, based on Next.js, PostgreSQL, Redis for caching and Amazon SQS for background jobs

### rabota08.ru | Elista CTO | 09/2021 - 01/2022

- Launched the alpha version which has 1000+ daily website clients and 500+ telegram readers
- Formulated the business model and multiple revenue sources with the CEO. With the current growth trajectory it could generate \$10.000+ monthly revenue in a span of one year
- Participated in hiring a SMM team, whose efforts resulted in 200%+ increased daily viewers

#### Busbud | Montreal, Quebec

### Senior fullstack developer (remote) | 08/2019 - 05/2021

- Added support for selling train tickets, which increased the amount of sold tickets by \$100.000+ monthly
- Spearheaded a russian adaptation: collaborated with translators, designers and marketers to modify the website to
  russian privacy laws laws and partners' APIs. It's a huge market with 60+ millions of active internet users and a potential
  for \$10.000.000+ in additional revenue
- Refactored parts of legacy backend codebase with TypeScript, improved test coverage to 80% with Jest, and reduced CI time by 30% which allowed to iterate much faster

Stack: TypeScript, Express.js, React.js/Redux, Jest, PostgreSQL, Docker.

### Vayable | San Francisco, California

### Full Stack Developer (remote) | 05/2019 - 08/2019

• Migrated legacy codebase from Rails 3 to Rails 5 in a span of two months.

- Moved to a React.js frontend, which allowed for many QoL features, improved performance and gave a foundation to mobile app
- Added JSON API with **30+** endpoints for the new frontend and partners
- Significantly improved test coverage with Rspec, FactoryBot and Capybara, which helped to reduce users' complaints by 80%

#### **Krypton Capital**

#### Full Stack Developer | 12/2017 - 05/2019

jury.online - an escrow platform for safe investments in blockchain startups

- Developed a MVP of a web dashboard for Ethereum smart contract in a span of 4 months from scratch
- Worked with Solidity developers to integrate smart contract with its 20+ public methods via Metamask Browser extension.
- Developed a JSON API with 40+ endpoints with accompanying Swagger documentation to be used by partners and upcoming React-based frontend

I was the only developer responsible for developing the dashboard in time before the ICO, and I have succeeded, helping the project to raise \$3.000.000+ in Ethereum investments.

**buzz.im** - a platform for advertising in Telegram messenger. Responsibilities:

- Optimized performance to achieve 90+ scoring on Google PageSpeed Insights
- · Improved SEO to get into top 3 positions in Google Search with the relevant keywords
- Worked with the developers of a telegram bot with 20+ JSON API endpoints to integrate its capabilities into the platform
- Developed a JSON API with accompanying Swagger documentation, which is used by Vue.js frontend
- Worked with with designers on mockups for a design revamp, integrated the resulting 30 screens into the platform.

#### Freelance | New York, New York

### Fullstack web developer (remote) | 02/2016 - 12/2017

Worked as a freelance Ruby on Rails developer under a guidance of Senior Software Developer from Zillow Group.

Built a template of a web application with Ruby on Rails that is being sold to startups in the real state business to help cut time for building MVPs in half

#### **Education**

#### Russian Business Leaders 2021

#### Exchange program

Russian Business Leaders is a competetive US State Department program for young Russians engaged in business leadership positions to gain exposure to work in the US private sector.

# Kalmyk State University | Elista

#### Bachelor's degree in Information Technology | 06/2017

Graduation project, called "Processing and analysis of the results of expert evaluation of a set of alternatives aka Delphi method" had received an excellent mark and was featured on local TV.